Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
Archive for the History of Quantum Physics, 1898-1950 (bulk)
Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
300.0 Microfilm reel(s) 12,500 items on 300 microfilm reels; 107 recordings
Primary source materials for the history of quantum physics in the twentieth century, collected under the auspices of the American Philosophical Society and the American Physical Society, with a grant from the National Science Foundation.
12,500 items on 300 microfilm reels; 107 recordings.
Abraham, Max, 1875-1922
Amaldi, Edoardo, 1908-1989
American Philosophical Society.
American Physical Society and American Philosophical Society.
American Physical Society.
Andrade, E. N. da C., (Edward Neville da Costa), 1887-1971
Back, Ernst, 1881-1959
Bauer, Edmond, 1880-1963
Becquerel, Jean, 1878-1953
Benedicks, Carl Axel Fredrik, 1875-1953
Berliner, Arnold, 1862-1942
Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980
Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962
Born, Max, 1882-1970
Breit, Gregory, 1899-1981
Broglie, Louis de, 1892-1987
Cockcroft, John, Sir, 1897-1967
Compton, Arthur Holly, 1892-1962
Coster, Dirk, 1889-1950
Darwin, Charles Galton, Sir, 1887-1962
Debye, Peter J. W., (Peter Josef William), 1884-1966
Dieke, Gerhard Heinrich, 1901-1965
Dirac, P. A. M., (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
Eddington, Arthur Stanley, Sir, 1882-1944
Ehrenfest, Paul, 1880-1933
Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954
Fokker, A. D., (Adriaan Daniel), 1887-1972
Fowler, A., (Alfred), 1868-1940
Franck, James, 1882-1964
Gerlach, Walther, 1889-1979
Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1902-1978
Haber, Fritz, 1868-1934
Heisenberg, Werner, 1901-1976
Hilbert, David, 1862-1943
Joliot-Curie, Frédéric
Jordan, Pascual, 1902-1980
Kamerlingh Onnes, Heike, 1853-1926
Kapitsa, P. L., (Petr Leonidovich), 1894-1984
Kayser, H., (Heinrich), 1853-1940
Kemble, Edwin C., (Edwin Crawford), 1889-1984
Klein, Oskar, 1894-1977
Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
Ladenburg, Rudolf Walter, 1882-1952
Langevin, Paul, 1872-1946
Laue, Max von, 1879-1960
London, Fritz, 1900-1954
McLennan, J. C., (John Cunningham), 1867-1935
Meitner, Lise, 1878-1968
Mie, Gustav, 1868-1957
Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953
Mulliken, Robert Sanderson, 1896-1986
Nishina, Yoshio, 1890-1951
Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967
Paschen, F., (Friedrich), 1865-1947
Pauli, Wolfgang, 1900-1958
Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994
Planck, Max, 1858-1947
Rosenfeld, L., (Leon), 1904-1974
Rosseland, Svein, 1894-1985
Rubens, Heinrich, 1865-1922
Runge, Carl, 1856-1927
Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937
Scheel, Karl, 1866-1936
Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961
Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951
Stark, Johannes, 1874-1957
Thomson, J. J., Sir, (Joseph John), 1856-1940
Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988
Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980
Voigt, Woldemar, 1850-1919
Von Neumann, John, 1903-1957
Warburg, Emil Gabriel, 1846-1931
Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1908-2002
Zeeman, Pieter, 1865-1943
Reel 300
Reel 108
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Initially purchased and accessioned, 1967. See in-house shelf list for additional dates and sources.
Existence and Location of Originals note
Originals of part of this collection are in: Niels Bohr Archives, Universitets Institut for Teoretisk Fysik, Copenhagen.
Other Finding Aids note
The collection is also described and analyzed in: Kuhn, Thomas S.; Heilbron, John L.; Forman, Paul; and Allen, Lini; eds., Sources for the History of Quantum Physics: An Inventory and Report, (Philadelphia: American Philosophical Society, 1967).
Related Archival Materials note
For transcripts of the oral history interviews, as well as the working papers of the Committee which includes correspondence with famous figures in physics, with some memoirs, photographs, lectures, etc., see Mss 530.1 Ar2.5.
Atomic theory.; Complementarity (Physics); Memoirs.; Oral histories; Photoprints.; Physicists.; Physics -- History.; Quantum theory -- History.; Relativity (Physics); Wave mechanics.
- I. Papers
  Scope and Contents note
  Collected papers of physicists preserved on microfilm by the Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 7 December 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Abraham, Max, 1875-1922 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 21 May 1898 - 28 January 1908; 17.0 Item(s) 17 letters (56 pages); Abraham, Max, 1875-1922 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Abrahamsen, E. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Academic Assistance Council. (Reel 10, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Academic Press. (Reel 12, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1904; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Ach, Narziss, 1871-1946 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 6 March 1920 - 8 July 1920; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); Adams, Edwin Plimpton, 1878-1956 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
    Unpublished material held elsewhere.
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 1923-1931, 2 letters.
    Palmer Physical Laboratory, Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey. Letters and memorabilia held in the Departmental office.
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1954; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Adrian, Edgar Douglas Adrian, Baron, 1889-1977 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Aerts, V. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924-1941; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (7 pages); Akademischer Verlag. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1, Reel 9, Reel 8)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Algemeen Nederlands Persbureau. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Algemene Nederlandse Vereniging voor Wijsbegeerte. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 15 October 1927 - 25 November 1927; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Allen, Herbert Stanley, 1873-1954 (Reel 61, Reel-frame 7)
    Unpublished material held elsewhere
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, October 25, 1923.
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (10 pages); Allen, Herbert Stanley, 1873-1954 (Reel 53, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Allen, J. F., (John Frank) (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933-1934; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Allison, Samuel King, 1900-1965 (Reel 53, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Amaldi, Edoardo, 1908-1989 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 3 letters, 1941-1942.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (6 pages); Ambassade van het Koninkrijk der Nederlanden. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1930-1936; 45.0 Item(s) 45 letters (67 pages); American Academy of Arts and Sciences. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (6 pages); American Association for the Advancement of Science. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); American Association for the Advancement of Science. (Reel 29, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); American Association of Physics Teachers. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); American Chemical Society. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933-1937; 12.0 Item(s) 12 letters (14 pages); American Institute of Physics. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1932-1933; 24.0 Item(s) 24 letters (65 pages); American Physical Society. (Reel 53, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 14 February 1919 - March 1922; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (7 pages); Andrade, E. N. da C., (Edward Neville da Costa), 1887-1971 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 17 letters, 1923-1957.
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 29 November 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Andrade, E. N. da C., (Edward Neville da Costa), 1887-1971 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 1)
    Bedford College Library, University of London, London, England. Letter to William Wilson, 1 letter, December 7, 1950.
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Andrews, Donald H., (Donald Hatch), 1898-1973 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1946-1947; 7.0 Item(s) 7 letters (9 pages); Ankara Universitesi. (Reel 37, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to to Albert Jan Staverman, 1947; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Arkel, A. E. van, (Anton Eduard), 1893-1976 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924-1925; 12.0 Item(s) 12 letters (21 pages); Arndt, Fritz, 1885-1969 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1920-1922; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (11 pages); Arrhenius, Svante, 1859-1927 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Arrhenius, Svante, 1859-1927 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Atkinson, Robert d'Escourt, 1898-1982 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letters (2 pages); Auer von Welsbach, Carl, Freiherr von, 1858-1929 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Auger, Pierre, 1899-1993 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1917; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Aurén, Tycho Emanuel Ericson (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Aurén, Tycho Emanuel Ericson (Reel 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1946-1954; 20.0 Item(s) 20 letters (31 pages); Austria. Österreichische Bundesregierung. (Reel 37, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 25 February 1929 - 1 June 1929; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (11 pages); Bacher, Robert F., (Robert Fox), 1905-2004 (Reel 63, Reel-frame 1-5)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948-1949; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Bacher, Robert F., (Robert Fox), 1905-2004 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, November 21, 1957.
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 23 December 1926 - 2 February 1930; 10.0 Item(s) 10 letters (24 pages); Back, Ernst, 1881-1959 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 9, Reel 61, Reel-frame 2-7, Reel 63, Reel-frame 5-6, Reel 64, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 7 March 1921 - 13 August 1921; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (11 pages); Back, Ernst, 1881-1959 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 2 April 1920 - 2 April 1935; 10.0 Item(s) 10 letters (36 pages); Back, Ernst, 1881-1959 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1911; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Baedeker, Karl, 1877-1914 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Baerwald, Hans G. (Reel 19, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Baerwald, Hans G. (Reel 4, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1911; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Baeyer, Otto von, b. 1877 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Bagge, E. R., (Erich Rudolf), 1912-1996 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Baker, J. B. (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bakker, Cornelis Jan, 1904-1960 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bakker, Cornelis Jan, 1904-1960 (Reel 17, Reel-frame A)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1921-1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (8 pages); Ballantine, Stuart, (Charles Stuart), 1897-1944 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bangham, D. H. (Reel 62, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Bargmann, V., (Valentine), 1908-1989 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Barkhausen, G. H. (Reel 29, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Barnes, John Landes, 1906-1976 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Barnett, Samuel Jackson, 1873-1956 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Pierre Weiss, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Barnett, Samuel Jackson, 1873-1956 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1915; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Barres, J. William (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1928-1937; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters (21 pages); Bartlett, James H., (James Holley), 1904-2000 (Reel 53, Reel-frame 9, Reel 51, Reel-frame 1, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Barton, Henry Askew, 1898-1983 (Reel 62, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Barton, Henry Askew, 1898-1983 (Reel 51, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Baruch, Herman Benjamin, 1872-1953 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1944; 9.0 Item(s) 9 letters (11 pages); Bataafsche Petroleum Maatschappij.; Rijks, H. J. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); The Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervinderlijke Wijsbergeerte. Rotterdam (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1907; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Battelli, Angelo, 1862-1916 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 6 November 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bauer, Edmond, 1880-1963 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letters to Fritz London, 6 letters, 1934-1936.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Bauer, Friedrich Ludwig, 1924- (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1926-1927; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Bauman, J. (Reel 61, Reel-frame 2, Reel 60, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Baur, Emil, b. 1873 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bazzoni, Charles B., (Charles Blizard), b. 1886 (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Anton David Udden, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bazzoni, Charles B., (Charles Blizard), b. 1886 (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 22 March 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bechert, Karl, 1901-1981; Catalan, Miguel Angel, 1894-1957 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 9 November 1934 - 1947; 15.0 Item(s) 15 letters (42 pages); Bechert, Karl, 1901-1981 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Bechmann, Rudolf (Reel 29, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 7 August 1924 - 1947; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (8 pages); Becker, Richard, 1887-1955 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2, Reel 11)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 25 July 1928 - 1 March 1939; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Becker, Richard, 1887-1955 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 8)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, December 9, 1923.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letter to Fritz London, October 25, 1937.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1947; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Becker, Wilhelm, 1907-1996 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 8 November 1930 - 1951; 75.0 Item(s) 75 letters (279 pages); Becquerel, Jean, 1878-1953 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 4, Reel 9, Reel-frame 2)
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin. Letter to Heinrich Kayser, undated. Darmstaedter Collection, Fic 1910.
    Rijksmuseum voor de Geschiedenis der Natuurwetenschappen, Leiden, Netherlands. Letter to Heike Kamerlingh Onnes, February 24, 1926; letter to W. Tuyn, 1952; letter to Institut International du Froid, 1930.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 5 letters, 1951.
  - Théorie du métamagnétisme, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s); Becquerel, Jean, 1878-1953 (Reel 9, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Begle, Edward G., (Edward Griffith), 1914-1978 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Belgium. Ministerie van Buitenlandsche Zaken. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1950; 21.0 Item(s) 21 letters (50 pages); Belinfante, F. J., (Frederik Jozef) (Reel 11, Reel-frame 5, Reel 9, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1951; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Belinfante, F. J., (Frederik Jozef) (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Calculations on aa* - a*a, n.d.; 4.0 p.; Belinfante, F. J., (Frederik Jozef) (Reel 9, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bell, H. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Bell, R. P., (Ronald Percy) (Reel 53, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bemolt van Loghum Slaterus, A. J., b. 1902 (Reel 12, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1943; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Benndorf, Hans, 1870-1953 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Berg, Lewis E. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Berg, W. van den (Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Bergh, J. E. van den (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1951; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bergmann, Ernst David, 1903-1975 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1916-1921; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (9 pages); Berlème, Aage (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 7 March 1916 - 7 June 1918; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Berliner, Arnold, 1862-1942 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 30 July 1924 - 20 August 1924; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Berliner, Arnold, 1862-1942 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Max Planck, 28 July 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Berliner, Arnold, 1862-1942 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 31 October 1933 - 28 August 1935; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (14 pages); Berliner, Arnold, 1862-1942 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 8)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, July 5, 1923.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Letter to Lewin, 1912. (Lewin)
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. Letter to Adolf Baginsky, 1904; to Paul Ehrlich, 1911; 2 letters to Elster and Geitel, 1913-1916; 4 letters to Anton Krause, 1916; 4 letters to Adolf Seitz, 1921-1926. (Darmstaedter Collection, G2 1900) Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, Munich, Germany. Letter to Franz Boll, 1916. Rijksmuseum voor de Geschiedenis der Natuurwetenschappen, Leiden, Netherlands. 5 Letters to Paul Ehrenfest, 1930-1931.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 5 items, 1919-1924; 2 items. 1930.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. 4 letters to Fritz London, 1929-1933.
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1954-1958; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (10 pages); Bertotti, B., 1930- (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1933-1935; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (11 pages); Beth, Erich (Reel 29, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Christian Møller, 25 March 1932 - 30 April 1932; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Bethe, Hans A., (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 5 January 1933 - 15 January 1933; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Bethe, Hans A., (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 9)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 11 letters, 1933-1954.
    Pauli Collection, Zurich, Switzerland.
    Cornell University Archives, Ithaca, New York. Personal papers.
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letter to Fritz London, 1934.
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1911-1912; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (9 pages); Betz, Albert, 1885-1968 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Beutler, Hans, 1896-1942 (Reel 41, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1935; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Beutler, Hans, 1896-1942 (Reel 29, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937-1950; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (11 pages); Bhabha, Homi Jehangir, 1909-1966 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 2, Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (6 pages); Bialobrzeski, Czeslaw (Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1950; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Bierens de Haan, J. A., (Johan Abraham), 1883-1958 (Reel 12, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (7 pages); Biezeno, Cornelis Benjamin, 1888-1975 (Reel 11, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1914-1920; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (30 pages); Biggs, Henry Francis (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, Circa 1926-1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Biggs, Henry Francis (Reel 41, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Bijl, Arie (Reel 9, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1945-1951; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (19 pages); Bijl, D. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 10 November 1919 - 28 April 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Edward Uhler Condon, 9 November 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980 (Reel 50, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 6 February 1923 - 12 November 1932; 67.0 Item(s) 67 letters; Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980 (Reel 50, Reel-frame 1-10)
  - Letters to J. H. Van Vleck, 16 June 1925 - 28 December 1928; 18.0 Item(s) 18 letters (28 pages); Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 2)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 9 letters, 1923-1955.
    Regional Cultural History Project, University of California, Berkeley, California. Autobiographical narrative prepared from tape-recorded interviews. (Microfilm copy at American Institute of Physics, New York.)
    American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. Autobiographical memoir. Tape-recorded interview. Correspondence and papers relating to American Association of Physics Teachers during 1930s. Letter to Gordon Fulcher, 1952.
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Birkhoff, George David, 1884-1944 (Reel 53, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to J. H. Van Vleck, 1929-1931; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Bitter, Francis, 1902-1967 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1920-1921; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Bjerknes, V., (Vilhelm), 1862-1951 (Reel BSC 1, Reel-frame 3)